<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pierce McGeough</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 11:39:24 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 11:39:24 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>AngularJs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;AngularJS is a JavaScript framework. It can be added to an HTML page with a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag.
AngularJS extends HTML attributes with Directives, and binds data to HTML with Expressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;javascript-framework&quot;&gt;JavaScript Framework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;is a JavaScript framework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;add with a script&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;script src=&quot;http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/angularjs/1.3.14/angular.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;extends HTML with new attributes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;perfect for Single Page Applications (SPAs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extends-html&quot;&gt;Extends HTML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ng-app&lt;/code&gt; - defines an Angular JS app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ng-model&lt;/code&gt; - binds the HTML value to app data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ng-bind&lt;/code&gt; - binds app data to HTML:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &amp;lt;div ng-app=&quot;&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Name: &amp;lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; ng-model=&quot;name&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p ng-bind=&quot;name&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//web-development/tutorial/2015/06/09/angularjs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//web-development/tutorial/2015/06/09/angularjs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>web-development</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guidelines for sending email</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a revision from a talk by at Smashing Conf Oxford 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-responsive&quot;&gt;Be Responsive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we need to make sure to have a good responsive layout. Most system users will likely signup using a desktop and then receive their first email straight away, however the majority of their follow up emails will most likely be read on a mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;67% of mobile internet activities is sending and receiving emails&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guides&quot;&gt;Guides&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While most of the email templates will cover these but we need to make sure we use them correctly especially when dealing with mobile layouts. These following guides are true for both desktop and mobile email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three general rules for mobile layouts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Eyeball&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Thumb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At arms length&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 Eyeball&lt;/strong&gt; – means that the user can read the email while being distracted. Important information will get noticed and remembered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 Thumb (mainly mobile)&lt;/strong&gt; – this means that any major calls to action are easily clickable. Minimum of 46px squared is a recommended size. Any other links should also be kept apart to avoid the user accidently clicking the wrong link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At arms length&lt;/strong&gt; – easy to read. Text size is recommended to be a minimum of 16px, images should be nicely sized and colour contrast should be adequate for the user to read with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;email-types&quot;&gt;Email Types&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we send emails we should note that there are four main purposes why we send them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy Me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Join Me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read Me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transactional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Me&lt;/strong&gt; – these emails are trying to sell the product (or an addon for the product). The copy should be concise with simple calls to action. Use images in these emails to build enticement for the user to spend money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join Me&lt;/strong&gt; – these emails are generally a notice or invitation to events. Copy in these is limited to important details and are clear for the user to see and easy to remember. Bold calls to action are used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read Me&lt;/strong&gt; – these are generally newsletter emails. While you may get large number to users who won’t read these you still need to make it as easy and pleasurable to read. We need to use well-written copy and make use of good typography which will help make large amounts of content easier to digest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transactional&lt;/strong&gt; – these emails convey receipts and order info (i.e. recurly). These should be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      &lt;strong&gt;Focused&lt;/strong&gt; – e.g. credit card / payment declined should not include anything else – no sales links or unnecessary information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      &lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive&lt;/strong&gt; – as much relative information as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      &lt;strong&gt;Appropriate&lt;/strong&gt; – no unnecessary images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      &lt;strong&gt;Practical&lt;/strong&gt; – message needs to be obvious to user. The content needs to be actionable (without being inappropriate) and these emails above the rest should be readable on all devices and easily printed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      &lt;strong&gt;Spartan&lt;/strong&gt; – No excess design. At the most it can have the regular branding used on all emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-emails&quot;&gt;Our Emails&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the emails we currently send I would say we fall into those four categories. We should remember to bring across any ShowHouse branding where possible i.e. colours, logos, call to action arrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;template&quot;&gt;Template&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we should keep to a minimal header and footer for our email template, which internal content changing.  Logo and ‘view online’ link as header followed by the contact details, copyright info and unsubscribe link in the footer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome&lt;/strong&gt; – this is a Join Me email. After the user signs up they receive this email. The important information included in this is their url, email, and (possibly) password. Bold ‘Get Started’ link the same as we use in the website. Secondary text and information can be a simple ‘Thank you for signing up’ and we should include, something like ‘This is a 14 day free trail to upgrade or cancel click here……’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Started&lt;/strong&gt; – as far as I am aware this gets sent out a day after initial signup. This is a Read Me type email but due to the nature of it (get started) should be as clear as possible and short as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invoice&lt;/strong&gt; – sent after a subscription is confirmed. This Transaction email works well as it is. If it is possible we should build it into our ShowHouse themed email with a minimal style header and footer. Unsubscribe shouldn’t be an option here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sales&lt;/strong&gt; – used to entice the user to sign up to ShowHouse. Buy Me type email. Again we can use the ‘Get Started’ arrow link from the website. Clear images of the product should be used i.e. screenshot of the properties list. An image of the calendar could be too general since many systems use calendars.  We can build different campaigns to suit potential customers i.e. Resident Lettings, Residential Sales or a general ShowHouse design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt; – This is a Read Me type email but once again because of its nature of being a Monthly Newsletter we can change the content slightly and introduce some Buy Me and Join Me elements too. When working with sections let us remember to keep the content easy to read using a nice typeface and meaningful images if we use them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//web-development/general/2015/04/27/email-guidelines.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//web-development/general/2015/04/27/email-guidelines.html</guid>
        
        <category>email</category>
        
        <category>responsive-email</category>
        
        
        <category>web-development</category>
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 20:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//web-development/general/2015/03/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//web-development/general/2015/03/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>web-development</category>
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Junior National Championships</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//kickboxing/general/2015/03/20/kbi-juniors.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://piercemcgeough.github.io/piercemcgeough//kickboxing/general/2015/03/20/kbi-juniors.html</guid>
        
        <category>national-championsips</category>
        
        <category>juniors</category>
        
        
        <category>kickboxing</category>
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
